Simone Maria Giancola

(+39) 3314788683 | Milan, Italy

simonegiancola@gmail.com | Personal Webpage simonegiancola09.github.io

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Motivated MS Student with a proficient academic record. Willing to broaden his knowledge of Data Science and apply formal methods in a real setting. Interested in Research and Analysis, especially using Machine Learning, Statistics and rigorous scientific methods.

EDUCATION

Bocconi University

Milan, ITA

MS Data Science

August 2021 - July 2023

- Modules include: Advanced Machine Learning, Optimization, Stochastic Processes
- Computationally oriented course, with a focus on theory and rigorous applications

Arizona State University

Phoenix, USA

January 2021 - May 2021

August 2018 - July 2021

 $Undergraduate\ Exchange\ Program$

• GPA 4.17 / 4.00, 4 classes

• Graduate level modules: Quantum Computation, Modeling with Game Theory

Bocconi University

Milan, ITA

BS Economics, Management and Computer Science

• Grade 110 Cum Laude / 110, final GPA 29.18 / 30

- Thesis: "Value of Information in a Support Vector Machine, an exploration"
- Modules include: Advaced Statistical Methods, Applied Mathematics, Machine Learning

EXPERIENCE

Research Assistant

January 2021 - May 2021

Milan, ITA

Bocconi University

- Advised by Professor Borgonovo Emanuele (course director)
- Conducted research on extraction of a Value of Information measure from a SVM algorithm
- Collaborated in weekly calls, discussion, programming and analysis of 4 research papers
- Delivered a theoretical document in the form of a thesis available on personal webpage

Technology Analyst

July 2020 - August 2020

Barclays Bank PLC

Radbroke, UK

- Assigned to Interactive Voice Response monitoring team
- Delivered documentation on main Application Performance Monitoring tools
- Raised > 1000 GBP in an internal charity fundraising for the NHS

MACHINE LEARNING PROJECTS

Heartbeat Classification and Disease Detection

September 2020

- Classified patients using a Random Forest after analysis and exploration
- Identified condition with 90% accuracy from a single heartbeat

COVID-19 Analysis | co-authored

April 2020

- Visualization and prediction with Italian data
- Estimated low boundary time to extinction of the pandemic with curve fitting

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Advanced Python: Keras, Tensorflow, Sklearn, Numpy, Matplolib, Scipy;

Certifications by DeepLearning. AI in Deep Learning and AI for Medicine. Credentials on personal webpage:

Intermediate R, SQL, Matlab, C++

Languages

English (Advanced) IELTS 8.0, Duolingo 140/160;

Italian (mothertongue); Spanish (Basic)